Now we're going to learn how to come into lasso with our first hand.
If you hoop towards the left, your first hand is going to be your right hand.
If you hoop towards the right, your first hand will be your left hand.
Since I hoop to the left, I'll start with my right hand, hold the hoop at your hip.
You're going to slowly start to turn in the direction you hoop as, as you bring the hoop up and in towards the chest and over the head.
Now I'll do it.
Turn towards the left, bring the hip in towards your chest, over the head, into lasso.
Let me describe that a little bit more now.
Again, starting at the hip, turn in the direction you hoop as, bring the hand in towards the heart center over the head.
What happens with our hand up here is when we turn, the hoop rolled across the thumb and into the palm of the hand into lasso.
Once you're in lasso, you want to try to actually grab the hoop and release.
This is going to give you a lot of control and it's going to make sure that you don't toss the hoop across the room.
Let's try it again. At your hip, turning toward the direction you hoop in, bringing the hoop up, the hoop rolls across the thumb and into the palm of the hand.
Then continuously rolls between the palm and the back of your hand in lasso.
You want to make sure that you're swinging your hoop on a nice horizontal plane keeping it over your head.
That looks great.
Nice.